Ferrell mss., ca. 1940-1999 LMC 2718
Lilly Library
Ferrell mss.
ca. 1940-1999
Lilly Library
Ferrell, Robert H.
LMC 2718
200000 Items
The Ferrell mss, ca. 1940-1999, consist of the papers, writings and correspondence of Indiana University Prof. Emeritus Robert H. Ferrell.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Robert H. Ferrell (b. 1921) is an American historian and author of several books on Harry S. Truman and the diplomatic history of the United States. He received a B.S. in Education from Bowling Green State University in 1946 and a Ph.D. from Yale in 1951. He served in the U.S. Army Air Forces during World War II and as an intelligence analyst in the U.S. Air Force during the Korean War. Ferrell began his career at Indiana University as an Assistant Professor in 1953, subsequently rising to the post of Distinguished Professor of History in 1974.
Arrangement
Organized into correspondence and writings. Correspondence arranged chronologically.
Scope and Content Note
The collection includes correspondence, original drafts of Ferrell's work, and accompanying research files.
Acquisition Information
Acquired: 2000, 2018
Presidents --United States --History --20th century.; Indiana University; Ferrell, Robert H.; Ferrell, Robert H. --Correspondence; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.
- Ferrell mss., ca. 1940-1999
  - Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Sep. 1979-Feb. 1980 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 1980-Oct. 1980 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1987-June 1987; July 1989 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1968-April 1969 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, May-Dec 1969 (Box 7)
  - H.S.T. Correspondence (Box 8)
  - Personal (Box 8)
  - Class materials (Box 8)
  - Grade books (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence / Manuscript, 1991-1992 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, Jan.-June 1965 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Aug.-Nov. 1966; 1987; 1988 (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous files (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, 1966, Dec.-1967, June (Box 20)
  - Correspondence / Manuscript, Oct. 1982-Aug. 1983 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence / Manuscript, Aug. 1983-Dec. 1984 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence / Manuscript, Feb.-Nov. 1993 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, Jan.-June 1985 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence / Manuscript, Oct. 1993-Aug. 1994 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence / Manuscript, Jan.-Oct. 1986 (Box 26)
  - Correspondence / Manuscript, 1992-1993 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 28)
  - Correspondence, June-Dec. 1990 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1989 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence, Jan.-Sep. 1990 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 32)
  - Correspondence, March 1995-Jan. 1996 (Box 33)
  - Correspondence, etc., 1991-1993 (Box 34)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1978-Aug. 1979 (Box 35)
  - Files (sorted correspondence) (Box 36)
  - Correspondence, April-October, 1981 (Box 37)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 38)
  - Correspondence, Dec. 1981-Feb. 1984 (Box 39)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 40)
  - Files (Box 41)
  - sorted correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 41)
  - Writings (Box 41)
  - revisionist historians (Box 41)
  - Sorted correspondence, 1958-1975 (Box 42)
  - Correspondence, 1955-1957 (Box 43)
  - Correspondence, April 1952-Sep. 1953 (Box 44)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 45)
  - Correspondence, Sep. 1953-April 1955 (Box 46)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 47)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 48)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 49)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 50)
  - Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 51)
  - Correspondence, 1995-1999 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 53)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 54)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 55)
  - Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 56)
  - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 57)
  - Correspondence, 1997-1999 (Box 58)
  - Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 59)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 60)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 61)
  - Correspondence, 1982-1985 (Box 62)
  - Correspondence, 1997-1999 (Box 63)
  - Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 64)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 65)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1981 (Box 66)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 67)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 68)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 69)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 70)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 71)
  - Correspondence, 1954-1959 (Box 72)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 73)
  - Correspondence, 1942-1948 (Box 74)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1966 (Box 75)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 76)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 77)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 78)
  - Correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box 79)
  - Correspondence, 1978-1981 (Box 80)
  - Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 81)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 82)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 83)
  - Correspondence, 1949-1952 (Box 84)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 85)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 86)
  - Correspondence, 1973; 1980-1984 (Box 87)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 88)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1987 (Box 89)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 90)
  - Correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 91)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 92)
  - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 93)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1994 (Box 94)
  - Correspondence, 1998-2001 (Box 95)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 96)
  - Correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 97)
  - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 98)
  - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 99)
  - Writings by others (Box 99)
  - American Diplomacy (Box 100)
  - Kyoto (Box 100)
  - etc. (Box 100)
  - Woodrow Wilson (Box 101)
  - Eisenhower Diaries (Box 101)
  - HST Autobiography (Box 101)
  - Writings (Box 102)
  - American Diplomacy, 4th ed. (Box 102)
  - N.A.N. (Box 102)
  - Manuscripts, misc. (Box 103)
  - Fighting Soldier (Box 103)
  - Correspondence, misc. 1984-1985 (Box 103)
  - Interviews (Box 104)
  - Student related? (Box 104)
  - Keep? (Box 104)
  - American Diplomacy, 3rd ed. (Box 105)
  - etc. (Box 105)
  - Interviews (continued) (Box 106)
  - Class materials (Box 106)
  - Rand McNally (Box 107)
  - Class materials (Box 108)
  - Eisenhower Diaries, vol. 1 and 2 (Box 108)
  - Rand McNally (Box 109)
  - Scribner's (Box 109)
  - Little-Brown (Box 109)
  - Eisenhower Diaries (Box 110)
  - NAN - Chapters 2-9 (Box 110)
  - Eisenhower Diaries (Box 111)
  - Truman (Box 112)
  - Writings (Box 113)
  - NAN (Box 113)
  - Choosing Truman (Box 113)
  - Writings (Box 114)
  - Truman (Box 114)
  - Truman in the Whitehouse (Box 114)
  - Dear Bess (Box 114)
  - Writings (Box 115)
  - Files (Box 116)
  - Shorter writings, 1960s-1970s (Box 116)
  - Truman (Box 117)
  - Files (Box 118)
  - Shorter writings (Box 118)
  - etc. (Box 118)
  - Writings: triplet (Box 119)
  - Writings (Box 120)
  - M, F, + H-W (Box 120)
  - Harper M.S. (Box 120)
  - Writings (Box 121)
  - Eisenhower Diaries (Box 121)
  - Writings (Box 122)
  - The Dying President (Box 122)
  - The Presidency of C. Coolidge (Box 122)
  - Triplet (Box 122)
  - The Kansas City Investigation (Box 122)
  - Writings (Box 123)
  - Ill-Advised (Box 123)
  - Autobio. of Grace Coolidge (Box 123)
  - In the Philippines and Okinawa (Box 123)
  - etc. (Box 123)
  - Writings (Box 124)
  - Clifford (Box 124)
  - Lawrence Memoir (Box 124)
  - Coolidge, the man and the pres. (Box 124)
  - Vice presidents (Box 124)
  - etc. (Box 124)
  - Writings (Box 125)
  - Writings (Box 126)
  - Truman and Pendergast (Box 126)
  - Kansas City Investigation (Box 126)
  - Rainbow Hoosier (Box 126)
  - Offprints, 1977-1993 (Box 127)
  - H.S. Truman, 1994 (Box 128)
  - Writings (Box 129)
  - New American Nation (Box 129)
  - Files (Box 129)
  - Writings (Box 130)
  - The Strange Deaths of President Harding (Box 130)
  - Holding the Line (Box 130)
  - Writings (Box 131)
  - Joseph D. Lawrence, Fighting Soldier (Box 131)
  - Bemis Festschriff (Box 131)
  - Truman and the Bomb (Box 131)
  - Writings (Box 132)
  - N.A.N. (Box 132)
  - Dear Bess (Box 132)
  - The Mad American President (Box 132)
  - Writings (Box 133)
  - They Dying President (Box 133)
  - Barber-Holding the Line (Box 133)
  - Writings (Box 134)
  - Truman (Box 134)
  - Harding (Box 134)
  - Coolidge (Box 134)
  - N.A.N. (Box 134)
  - Writings (Box 135)
  - Harding (Box 135)
  - D.A.H. (Box 135)
  - Ernest Ferrell (Box 135)
  - Waterville Bank (Box 135)
  - Files with publishers (Box 136)
  - Etc. (Box 136)
  - Writings (Box 137)
  - Wilson (Box 137)
  - Truman (Box 137)
  - Coolidge (Box 137)
  - Etc. (Box 137)
  - Writings (Box 138)
  - Dana ms. (Box 138)
  - And shorter writings (Box 138)
  - Writings (Box 139)
  - Ill Advised (Box 139)
  - Etc. (Box 139)
  - Files (Box 139)
  - Subject files (Box 140)
  - Files (Box 141)
  - Subject Files (Box 141)
  - Etc. (Box 141)
  - Files (Box 142)
  - Writings (Box 143)
  - Strange Deaths of Harding (Box 143)
  - Etc. (Box 143)
  - Files (Box 144)
  - Files (Box 145)
  - Brooklyn College (Box 145)
  - Indiana University (Box 145)
  - SHAFR (Box 145)
  - Writings (Box 146)
  - American Diplomacy (Box 146)
  - Writings (Box 147)
  - American Diplomacy (Box 147)
  - The Rev. in AFP (Box 147)
  - Atlas of American History (Box 147)
  - Files (Box 148)
  - Writings (Box 149)
  - Choosing Truman (Box 149)
  - The Dying President (Box 149)
  - Adding the Line (Box 149)
  - Writings (Box 150)
  - America: A history of the people (Box 150)
  - Writings (Box 151)
  - They Dying President: FDR (Box 151)
  - The Presidency of C. Coolidge (Box 151)
  - Writings by Others (Box 152)
  - Bart Bernstein (Box 152)
  - Walker autobiography (Box 152)
  - Weeks ms. (Box 152)
  - Writings (Box 153)
  - The Presidency of C. Coolidge (Box 153)
  - Writings (Box 154)
  - Triplet memoir (Box 154)
  - Crowell (Box 154)
  - Carl Anthony (Box 154)
  - Writings (Box 155)
  - FDR's quiet confidant (Box 155)
  - Walker autobiography (Box 155)
  - Politics of Integrity (Box 155)
  - Encyclopedia of the American Pres. (Box 155)
  - The presidency of C. Coolidge (Box 155)
  - Triplet (Box 155)
  - Writings by Others (Box 156)
  - E. Ferrell-Stories.... (Box 156)
  - Kneeshaw ms. (Box 156)
  - Bogle-Madison and Indy RR (Box 156)
  - Writings (Box 157)
  - Article on Publishing (Box 157)
  - Torchbooks (Box 157)
  - AIADW (Box 157)
  - AAWP (Box 157)
  - Writings (Box 158)
  - Truman- Family Farm (Box 158)
  - Dana (Box 158)
  - Etc. (Box 158)
  - Writings (Box 159)
  - Barber mss. (Box 159)
  - Off the Record (Box 159)
  - Clippings (Truman, 1983) (Box 160)
  - Writings (Box 161)
  - Off the Record (Box 161)
  - Etc. (Box 161)
  - Writings (Box 162)
  - Harry S. Truman- a life (Box 162)
  - Writings (Box 163)
  - Banners in the Air (Box 163)
  - Gruenther ms. (Box 163)
  - Etc. (Box 163)
  - Note card files (Box 164)
  - Writings (Box 165)
  - Ill Advised (Box 165)
  - Eisenhower and the doctors (Box 165)
  - Truman and the Pendargast (Box 165)
  - The Dying President (Box 165)
  - The Strange Deaths (Box 165)
  - Note card files (Box 166)
  - Writings (Box 167)
  - Truman Centenary (Box 167)
  - Note card files (Box 168)
  - Writings (Box 169)
  - Eisenhower diaries (Box 169)
  - Leftovers (Box 169)
  - PPHST (Box 169)
  - Writings (Box 170)
  - PPHST (Box 170)
  - SHAFR bibl. (Box 170)
  - Barber ms. (Box 170)
  - Baker articles (Box 170)
  - Files (Box 171)
  - Conf. on Euro. Problems (Box 171)
  - SHAFR (Box 171)
  - Etc. (Box 171)
  - Course files (Box 172)
  - Writings by Others (Box 172)
  - Clippings (Box 173)
  - Offprints (Box 173)
  - Printed Material (Box 173)
  - Writings by others (Box 173)
  - Writings (Box 174)
  - Coolidge (Box 174)
  - Truman (Box 174)
  - Writings (Box 175)
  - Triplet (Box 175)
  - Am. Diplomacy, 20th e. (Box 175)
  - Short writings (Box 175)
  - Bemis Fest. (Box 176)
  - Writings by others (Box 176)
  - Writings by others (Box 177)
  - Writings (Box 178 (Oversize))
  - Truman (Box 178 (Oversize))
  - Holding the Line (Box 178 (Oversize))
  - Pamphlets (2 folders) (Box 179)
  - The Review of Politics (3 folders) (Box 179)
  - Modern Age (3 folders) (Box 179)
  - Journal of International Affairs (Box 179)
  - Journal of the Illinois State Historical Society (Box 179)
  - Indiana Academy of the Social Sciences (Box 179)
  - The Historian (Box 179)
  - Ohio Historical Quarterly (Box 179)
  - Ferrell misc., 01/04-12/04 (Box 180)
  - Halleck, Lowenthal, Graham, Dana, Beer, Truman anecdotes (Box 181)
  - Ferrell correspondence, cards, mss. Fleming (300 pp.), 03/03-11/03 (Box 182)
  - Truman misc. folders 1-20 (Box 183)
  - Truman misc. folders 21-39 (Box 184)
  - Truman "Dear Bess" letters, 1910-1936 (Box 185)
  - Truman "Dear Bess" letters, 1937-1959 (Box 186)
  - Ferrell correspondence, Harding, Jefferson/Hemings, etc., 01/12-09/12 (Box 187)
  - Ferrell correspondence, Bulufsky mss., Persico mss., Truman (Ferrell) mss., 12/03-02/04 (Box 188)
  - Ferrell correspondence, bills/receipts, Prybyla, Woodley, Pearlman, 12/04-05/05; 2004 (Box 189)
  - Ferrell correspondence, 07/02-03/03 (Box 190)
  - Truman misc., Pendergast, IU alumnis Dan Holtrop, Krasnoff (Box 191)
  - Ferrell-Truman mss., Congressional Quarterly, Step-by-Step, and correspondence (Box 192)
  - Ferrell correspondence, Morganthau/Mazur, OAH Magazine, 11/05-06/06 (Box 193)
  - Ferrell correspondence (missing 12/06), Kansas Historical Records, esp. Allen, 07/06-01/07 (Box 194)
  - Ferrell correspondence, 01/07-08/07 (Box 195)
  - Ferrell correspondence (missing 04/09), G.H.W. Bush Diary mss., 10/08-06/09 (Box 196)
  - Ferrell correspondence, 08/07-09/08 (Box 197)
  - Ferrell correspondence (missing 08/09), 06/09-03/10; 04/11-05/11 (Box 198)
  - Mss. Kertesz, Triplet, Coolidge, Britton, Dumar, Meredith (Box 199)
  - Mss. Baker Diary, Smoot Diary (2 vols.), MacArthur letters (Box 200)
  - Ferrell correspondence, IMH, Ashland University, Kirkendahl, Adams, 05/05-11/05 (Box 201)
  - Truman "Dear Bess" letters, duplicates (Box 202)
  - Truman "Dear Bess" letters, duplicates (Box 203)
  - Ferrell papers when a student at Yale: chapters, essays, misc. (Box 204)
  - Ferrell correspondence, 2008-2009 (Box 205)
  - Ferrell correspondence, Proznik, 04/10-02/11 (Box 206)
  - Ferrell correspondence, "Aid in Editing Drafts", 06/11-03/14 (Box 207)
  - Ferrell correspondence, Christmas cards, 12/12-08/13 (Box 208)
  - Ferrell correspondence, 09/14-02/16 (Box 209)
  - "Unjustly Dishonored: The 92nd Division." Copies of original documents (Box 210)
  - MacArthur (Box 211)
  - Presidency of Calvin Coolidge (Box 211)
  - Truman in the White House (Box 211)
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 211)
  - Compact discs (Box 211)
  - Floyd D. Ross (Box 212)
  - VHS tapes (Box 212)
  - Elmer W. Sherwood (Box 213)
  - Collapse at Meuse-Argonne (Box 213)
  - Harry S. Truman and the Revisionists (Box 213)
  - Writings by others, some sent to Ferrell for review and editing (Box 214)
  - Correspondence (Box 215)
  - Various essays (Box 215)
  - Diaries, 1949-1983 (Box 216)
  - Diaries, 1984-1999 (Box 217)
  - Diaries, 2000-2014 (Box 218)
  - Dissertations (Box 219)
  - John W. Ryan (Box 219)
  - America's Deadliest Battle (Box 220)
  - Stackpole Diary (Box 220)
  - Speeches and talks (Box 221)
  - Uncle Ivan letters (Box 221)
  - Assorted maps (Box 222)
- 2022 Additions
  - Charles E. Blankenship Correspondence, 1991-2019 (Box 222)
    - 1991-1999 (Box 222)
    - 2000-2009 (Box 222)
    - 2010-2018 (Box 222)
    - Obituaries, 2018 (Box 222)